Hello, I'm Kyle Brayer and your next in-home leg workout will be the alternating side lunge.
This is going to work the hip flexors as well as the glutes, hamstrings and quads once again.
Karie's going to start in her athletic stance with her feet just about shoulder-width apart.
She's going to keep her torso, so from her hips to her shoulders, in line once again.
She'll put her hands on her hips and she's going to step out with that left leg into a squatted position, and then she's going to come back up, and that will be one repetition.
Now she'll come back to the right, squat, and then come back across.
So she's not only getting the side lunge, which is working the hip flexors, but she's also getting a squat in this exercise.
Let's do one more like that, Karie.
Here she's going to step out to the right, she's going to come down, again, trying to keep those knees behind the toes, so lean back just a little bit for me, Karie.
There you go.
Then she'll come back and we'll go with the left leg.
Down and back up.
The negative portion, you can turn forward, the negative portion is when she's going down, that's the easier portion of the exercise so she'll be inhaling, and then as she comes back up she'll be exhaling.
That's the alternating side lunge.